(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-07-29T09:13:03.443806",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
どアニメ宣言！JOYSOUND
Do Anime Sengen! Joysound
アニメにハマって歌いたくなっちゃった
I got so into anime that I wanted to sing!
推しのシーン見ながらカラオケ歌えるなんて…
To be able to sing karaoke while watching my favorite scenes...
尊すぎてつらい！
It's too precious to handle!
歌いたいアニメ・ゲームソング見つけよう！
Let's find anime and game songs you want to sing!
アニソン・ゲーソン！
Anison & Gameson!
ねえ、今日はどこ行く？
Hey, where are we going today?
Yahoo!カーナビ推しドラ好評販売中！
Yahoo! Car Navi Oshi-Dora on sale now!
今ならダブル購入で兎田ぺこらとの掛け合いボイスが聞けちゃう！
Buy both now to hear banter voices with Usada Pekora!
AZKiと一緒にドライブしよう！
Let's drive together with AZKi!
「推しドラ」で検索！
Search for "Oshi-Dora"!
生きることをやめないでと
Don't stop living,
私が今歌う
I'm singing now
ずっとひとりぼっちだね
You've always been all alone,
空の青さ知らずに
Without knowing the blueness of the sky
ひとつふたつみっつめの
One, two, three
後悔を抱きしめて
Embracing the regrets
泣いてたくって泣いてたくって
Crying and crying,
泣いてたくって笑えなくなる
Crying so much I can't even smile
もう消えてしまいたい
I just want to disappear already
立ち止まって立ち止まって
Stopping and stopping,
立ち止まって歩けなくなる
Stopping so much I can't walk anymore
でも心は叫んでる
Yet my heart is screaming
生きることをやめないでと
Don't stop living,
私が今歌うよ
I'm singing now
本当は終わるはずだった命
A life that was supposed to end
抱いてここにいたいと願った
I wished to hold it and stay here
君は幸せでしたか
Were you happy?
私は幸せにできたかな
I wonder if I made you happy
愛しくって愛しくって
So dear, so dear,
愛しくって近づくたびに
So dear, every time I get closer
なぜ失いたくない
Why don't I want to lose it?
怖くなって怖くなって
Becoming scared, becoming scared,
怖くなって遠ざかっていく
Becoming scared and drifting away
またいつかひとり別れを告げ
Saying goodbye to someone alone once more
それでも今を生きていくの
Still living in the present
生きていくよ
I'll keep living
この気持ちだけは
Only this feeling
嘘じゃない嘘じゃない
Is not a lie, not a lie
嘘じゃない
Not a lie
この手に握ったもの
What I grasped in this hand
この涙に宿るもの
What dwells in these tears
明日へつないでくれたんだよ
Connected me to tomorrow
この目に映ったもの
What was reflected in these eyes
この心に響くもの
What resonates in this heart
未来へきっといつまでも
Surely toward the future, forever
生きることをやめないでと
Don't stop living,
私に今
To me now
生きることをやめないでと
Don't stop living,
私が今歌うよ
I'm singing now
誰にも言えなかった後悔を
Regrets I couldn't tell anyone
さよならここに置いていくから
I'll leave here saying goodbye
生きることをやめないでと
Don't stop living,
私が今歌う
I sing now.
ずっとひとりぼっちだね
You're always all alone,
空の青さ知らずに
Without knowing the blue of the sky.
ひとつふたつみつめての
Staring at one or two things,
後悔を抱きしめて
Embracing the regrets.
泣きたくて泣きたくて
Wanting to cry, wanting to cry,
泣きたくて笑えなくなる
Wanting to cry until I can't smile.
もう消えてしまいたい
I want to disappear already.
立ち止まって立ち止まって
Stopping and stopping,
立ち止まって歩けなくなる
Stopping until I can't walk anymore,
でも心は叫んでる
But my heart is shouting:
生きることをやめないでと
"Don't stop living,"
私が今歌うよ
I am singing now.
本当は終わるはずだった命
A life that was supposed to end,
抱えてここにいたいと願った
Wishing to hold it and stay right here.
君は幸せでしたか
Were you happy?
私は幸せにできたかな
Could I make you happy?
愛おしくて愛おしくて
So dear, so dear,
愛おしくて近づくたびに
So dear, every time I get closer,
なぜ失いたくない
Why don't I want to lose you?
怖くなって怖くなって
Becoming so afraid, so afraid,
怖くなって遠ざかっていく
Growing afraid and drifting away.
またいつかひとり別れを告げ
Saying goodbye alone once again,
それでも今を生きていくの
Yet still living in the present,
生きていくよ
I will keep living.
この気持ちだけは
This feeling alone...
嘘じゃない嘘じゃない
Is not a lie, is not a lie,
嘘じゃない
It is not a lie.
本日はAZKi SOLO LIVE 2025 Departureにご来場いただき、ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much for coming to AZKi Solo Live 2025 "Departure" today!
こんこんこんこん、こあずきー！
Hello, hello, hello, hello, Koazuki!
あ、みんな元気いいですね。
Ah, everyone's got great energy, huh?
右手にマイク、左手に地図、あなたのハートをゼロゲットさ、AZKiです！
Microphone in my right hand, map in my left, zero-getting your heart—I'm AZKi!
最後までライブを安心して楽しんでいただくために、いくつかご案内させていただきます。
To ensure you can enjoy the concert safely until the very end, we have a few announcements.
公演中の撮影、録音、録画機材の使用は固くお断りいたします。
The use of recording, audio, or video equipment during the performance is strictly prohibited.
館内は禁煙となっております。喫煙はご遠慮ください。
The venue is non-smoking. Please refrain from smoking.
万が一、具合が悪くなってしまった場合は無理をせず近くのスタッフへお知らせください。
If you happen to feel unwell, please do not push yourself and notify nearby staff.
会場内でのモッシュ、ダイブ、ステージにものを投げ込むなど、他のみんなの迷惑になったり公演を妨げる行為は一切禁止です！ルールを守って盛り上がってください！
Mosh pits, stage diving, throwing objects onto the stage, or any other nuisances or disruptions are strictly prohibited! Please follow the rules and enjoy the show!
また、本公演は映像配信及び写真撮影用のカメラが会場内に入り、客席が映り込む場合があります。
Also, cameras for video streaming and photography may enter the venue and capture the audience.
これらの映像や写真はプロモーション等に使用される可能性がありますので、あらかじめご容赦ください。
Please be aware that these images and photos may be used for promotions and such.
また、ライブのハッシュタグは「AZKiと未来へ」です！
Also, the live hashtag is "#AZKiToMiraiE"!
ハッシュタグを使ってたくさん盛り上げてくれると嬉しいです。
We'd be so happy if you use the hashtag to hype things up!
それでは、開演までもう少しです！みんなの声、いっぱい聞かせてねー！
Well then, curtain time is almost here! Let us hear your voices loud and clear!
もっとわ…
More...
もっとわーーー…
鏡よ教えて 私の新しい
Mirror, tell me, my new...
ずっとひとりぼっちだった
I was always all alone,
教室のいちばん陽で
in the corner of the classroom.
ずっと考え続けていた
I kept thinking for a long time:
「私が生きる意味は何だろう？」って
"What is the meaning of my existence?"
運命の津波が押し寄せてきたんだ
The tsunami of fate came rushing in,
何すべきかもわからずに立ち尽くしてた
I stood there stunned, not knowing what to do.
幾星霜の刻が歯車を狂わせて
The gears of time have gone wrong.
時計の針はもう二度と巻き戻せない
The clock hands can never be turned back.
だからどんなに過去が悔やみきれなくても
So no matter how much you regret the past,
進むべき道は未来しかないんだ
the only way forward is the future.
これが私に科された運命だとしても
Even if this was the fate imposed on me,
もう少しだけ歩きたかったあなたの傍で
I wanted to walk just a little longer by your side.
全てが色褪せていく
Everything is fading away,
虚空の世界を彩る
coloring the world of emptiness.
爛々とそよぐ風が
The firelight and the swaying wind
水面揺らし大地染める
make the water's surface tremble and dye the earth.
光と影が織りなし照らす
Light and shadow weave together and illuminate
約束の場所への道標を
the signpost to the promised place.
あなたがいる、この世界で
In this world where you are,
きっとまた巡り合えるから
I'm sure we can meet again.
約束をしようよ
Let's make a promise.
だからどんなに遠く離れてしまっても
So no matter how far apart we are,
必ずあなたに逢いに行くよ
I will definitely come to see you.
だからどんな姿に生まれ変わっても
So no matter what form you are reborn in,
私の事を思い出してくれますか？
will you remember me?
（遥かな時を超え）
(Beyond the distant time...)
（あなたに逢いたい...）
(I want to see you...)
この扉の向こうが未知の可能性なら
If the door ahead is a land of unknown possibilities,
今を動かせるの？
can you move the present?
暗闇を探索で
Searching in the darkness,
不安と焦燥の中
amidst anxiety and impatience,
こぼれる光を見た
I saw overflowing light.
手を伸ばしてこの先は
Reaching out my hand, because this path
君のものだから
is yours.
時を超えて
Beyond time,
繋がるよ 心が今
our hearts are connected now.
想像するの 私のストーリー
I'm creating my own story.
声を聴かせて 君を知りたいから
Let me hear your voice, because I want to know you.
輝かせよう 新しい世界
Let's make this new world shine.
生まれた意味を見つけるのさ
I'll find the meaning of my birth.
全てが始まる この場所で
Everything begins in this place.
声を枯れるまで叫んで
Shouting until my voice becomes hoarse,
言葉に傷つけられて
being hurt by words...
悲しみがこぼれるのは
It's not because I'm weak
弱いからじゃないよ
that sorrow overflows.
勇気はあるから
Because the courage is here,
かき消されちゃいけないんだ
it must not be erased.
君は君のままでいい
It's okay for you to be you.
声を上げて私たちの歌は壊れない
Raising our voices, our song will not break.
何回だって
No matter how many times,
伝えるよ 心を今
I'll convey my heart now.
共鳴するの 私のストーリー
My story resonates.
名前を呼んで 側にいるから
Calling your name, because I'm by your side.
音を奏でよう 新しい世界
Let's play the sound of this new world.
君に出会うために生きていくんだ
I'm living to meet you.
この場所が奇跡だから
Because this place is a miracle,
リアルを越えて繋ぐよ、さあ
crossing reality, I will connect.
夜は深く眠りに落ちて
The night falls into a deep sleep,
やがて光が世界を照らすよ
eventually, the light will illuminate the world.
君と出会えたこと
Having met you,
意味を見つけたのさ
I found the meaning.
共に分かち合って生きたい
I want to share and live.
想像するの 私のストーリー
I'm creating my own story.
声を聴かせて 君を知りたいから
Let me hear your voice, because I want to know you.
開拓するの 新しい世界
I will pioneer this new world.
生まれる前から
Even before I was born,
遠きを恋うて
longing for faraway places,
募るよ 心が今
my heart is growing stronger right now.
想像するのは 私のストーリー
What I imagine is my own story.
ごめんね 聞かせてよ 君を知りたいから
Sorry, let me hear about you, because I want to know you.
輝かせよう 新しい世界
Let's make a new world shine bright.
生まれた意味を見つけるときさ すべてが始まる
When you find the meaning of birth, everything begins
この場所で
in this place,
声が枯れるまで 叫んで
shouting until my voice goes hoarse.
答えを教えてよ 宵闇おぼろげメランコリー
Tell me the answer, twilight's dim melancholy.
体と感情が交差する 正しい自分は何？
Where body and emotions intersect, what is the right me?
二度とさようならを言わないで 交差する 世界は一つじゃない
Never saying goodbye again, intersecting worlds are not just one.
「いいね」とフォロワーの数字 増えていく 盲目にセオリー振りかざして
Likes and follower numbers increase, brandishing theories blindly
そして 首を締める
and tightening around the neck.
私の生きる世界は 自分の手で選ばせてよ
Let me choose the world I live in with my own hands.
真夜中のメランコリー 生まれ変わるアイデンティティ 好みがこの辺が痛いよ
Midnight melancholy, reborn identity, this liking, this area hurts.
上っ面らの泣き所 知り尽くしてく 可愛いフェイス
Knowing all the shallow crying spots, a cute face.
私を 私を 誰かにとって
Make me, make me, for someone else,
変わるの
change.
どんどんいくよ！ 見てって見てって！
Going more and more! Look at me, look at me!
どうして 気付いてしまったの 熱くなるほどに 隠しきれない戸惑い
Why did I realize it? Growing so warm, bewilderment I can't hide.
ぎこちない距離 およそ話しして
An awkward distance, talking roughly,
揺れる心 拭えない日より
a wavering heart, days I can't wipe away.
人知れず響く胸の鼓動 高級ステイままならないのに
A heart beating in secret, even though high-end stay isn't working out.
きっとどこかで願っているんだ
I'm sure I'm wishing somewhere
終わりのない時間を
for endless time.
恋の始まりは 誰も知らない 私だけの宝物を
The start of love is a treasure known to no one else, mine alone.
少しでも言葉が鳴ったりしたら 日だまりのような笑顔も
If my words ring out even a little, smiles like a sunny spot too
とっさに振る舞う仕草も 全部 なくしてしまうそうして
and gestures made on impulse—I'd lose them all, and then
もしもひとつだけ叶うのならば ただ君のすぐ隣で 過ぎていく季節眺めていたい
if only one wish could come true, I'd just want to watch the passing seasons right by your side.
溢れそうな肌の思いは 胸の奥にしまいこんだ
Feelings of skin on the verge of overflowing, tucked deep in my chest.
ふたりの声が空に 吸い込まれていく
Our voices are getting sucked up into the sky.
閉ざした世界 かすかに聞こえる音 世界でふたり 切り離して
A closed world, a faint sound, separating the two of us in the world.
届きそうだって すれ違った心臓が
Hearts that seemed to reach each other, passing by one another,
ちょっと痛んだ無駄
aching a little in vain.
ここで待って ここでまって ここでまって
Wait here, wait here, wait here.
決められないままで とまどい溢れてしまうよ
Remaining undecided, bewilderment overflows.
もう何度も繰り返した
I've repeated it so many times already.
こぼれた想いを数えて
Counting the spilled feelings,
何度も繰り返した 世界 世界
over and over, repeating this world, this world,
秘密のままでいる
keeping it a secret.
まだまだ盛り上がっていくよ！
Let's keep the energy going!
もっと声出せるよね！
I know you can give me more voice!
バカバカしいな 不自由な思考
It's so foolish, this restricted thinking.
意味がないなら楽しい歌も
If it has no meaning, even joyful songs
責めてく人 逃げてく人 良くないひとに
Those who blame, those who run, those who aren't great—
息苦しくなる
it suffocates me.
前向いちゃうね
Looking ahead anyway,
狂った世界で僕らはみんな生きているから
in this mad world, we're all just trying to live,
好きに殴り合ってどうしかしてしまう
so we beat each other up as we please and lose our minds.
ニュースが流れ大事件に涙を流す人はいない
The news plays, but no one sheds a tear over major incidents.
ビルージェンが嘘の街 姿が抜け出せ
Buildings stand in a town of lies, unable to escape their forms.
光の街へ
To the city of light.
めぐれラスト セング！セング！セング！
Spin around, final stage! Stage! Stage!
見せもんばかりすべて上ベでかざってごまかして
Only showing off superficial things, dressing them up and masking them.
何が正解かが分からないから壊れていく
Not knowing what the right answer is, everything breaks apart.
いったい何が本当なんだっけ？
What on earth is actually real anymore?
期待しても泣き出せってばかどいつもこいつもしん
Even if I hope, I end up crying—every single one of them...
ばすよ
is rotten.
こんな異常だけの世界で存在探し出してるんだ
Searching for existence in such an abnormal world,
欲望の無い自由なリアどこへ行くのか
where is desire-free freedom heading?
こんな異常だけの世界で存在探し出してるんだ
Searching for existence in such an abnormal world,
何を言われても満たされることないよ
no matter what anyone says, I'll never be fulfilled.
感覚ずれてすべて忘れ
Senses skewed, forgetting everything.
はい、えーということで
Right, uh, so...
AZKi 7th Live 2025 デパーチャーへ、ようこそ！
Welcome to AZKi 7th Live 2025 Departure!
あーちょっと歌いすぎた
Ah, I sang a bit too much.
歌いすぎました
I sang way too much.
みわたす限り開拓者！
As far as the eye can see, pioneers!
本当に、もうこの景色を見て胸がいっぱいになってしまっているんですが
Really, just seeing this scenery fills my heart to the brim, but...
今日はAZKiにとって初めてのアリーナでのソロライブです。
Today is AZKi's very first arena solo live.
この景色本当に胸がいっぱいで…まだまだ早いか、まだこの間だ
This scenery truly fills my heart... Is it too early? Not yet, just a moment ago.
ということで、みんな今日はね、貴重な一日をこのAZKiのライブのために時間を作ってくれてありがとうございます。
So everyone, thank you so much for taking time out of your precious day today for AZKi's live.
早速なんですが、メドレーどうでした？
Right away, how was the medley?
ありがとうございます！そしてもちろん！
Thank you! And of course,
1曲目はこの曲と決めていました、「未来カプセラ」ということで
I had decided this song would be the first one, "Mirai Capsuleer"—
新EPから、えっと、リスタートから1曲目をお届けしましたが、みんなEPは聴いてくれましたか？
We delivered the first song from the new EP, from Restart—did everyone listen to the EP?
ありがとうございます！
Thank you!
そしてそして、本日の衣装どうですか？
And, and, how is today's outfit?
いいですよね！すぐね、3Dビジュアルでみんなこの衣装来るんじゃないかと思ってたと思うんですけど
It's great, right? Right away in 3D visuals, I thought everyone might expect this outfit, but...
なんと
guess what...
スタイリストして、黒のカラーバリエーションを作っていただきましたー！
The stylist created black color variations for me!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
そして、今日のね、素敵なステージでございます。
And, here is today's wonderful stage.
みんな、装飾、気づきました？
Did everyone notice the decoration?
変化してたの気づきました？この上のね、この今「アリュール」っていう、あっ、あっ、ピカピカピカピカ
Did you notice it changed? Up here, this... right now, "Aperture"—ah, ah, shiny, shiny, shiny, shiny...
ピカピカピカピカ！ありがとうございます！
Shiny, shiny, shiny, shiny! Thank you very much!
この変化気づきましたでしょうか？
Did you notice this change?
曲のね、頭で実わ、あの、このアルファの装飾部分がですね、あの、色が変わってまして
Actually, at the beginning of the song, the decoration part of this Alpha... the color changed,
みんなちょっと、あの、続いての大変だったよね、この色にしてくださいっていうペンライトカラーになっておりました！本当に曲の冒頭の方なので、あの、見られた方は
and everyone... it was quite something to match this pen light color! Since it's right at the beginning of the song, for those who saw it...
ありがとう！あの、帰っていただけたらなと思います。
Thank you! I hope you can go back and check it out.
それに合わせてね、みんなペンライト点灯していただいたり、
Along with that, please turn on your pen lights,
2色光ったときはですね、ペンライトも2色にしてください！
and when two colors shine, please make the pen lights two colors too!
みんなで一緒に今日のライブを作っていこー！よろしくお願いします！
Let's make today's live together! Thank you!
ということで、えー、今日のライブはですね、え、バンドメンバーと一緒にお届けしてあります！
So, for today's live, we are delivering it together with the band members!
すごい、素晴らしい演奏ありがとうございます！しかもなんと、
Amazing, thank you for the wonderful performance! And what's more,
え、今回はですね、ヴァイオリンも参加しております！
um, this time, a violin is also participating!
ありがとうございます！え、今日のために、え、特別にアレンジした楽曲もたくさんあるので、お楽しみに！
Thank you very much! There are many specially arranged songs for today, so please look forward to it!
そして今日はね、現地のみんなだけじゃなくてですね、配信で見てくれる開拓者もいます！配信のみんなーー！
And today, not only everyone here on-site, but also pioneers watching via stream! Everyone on the stream!
はい、コメントも見えてる！うおー、いぇー！
Yes, I can see the comments! Woo, yeah!
あずきち、ふー、いぇー！あずりんがすごーい！ありがとうございます！
Azukichi, hoo, yeah! Azurin is amazing! Thank you very much!
ということで、本日は、え、ハッシュタグ「あずきと未来へ」で今日の感想や、
So, today, please post your impressions of today or memorable moments
え、印象に残った瞬間をポストしてください！あとで全部見に行きまーす！よろしくお願いしまーす！
using the hashtag "AZKi and to the future"! I'll go check them all out later! Thank you!
配信のみんなのスクショもよろしく！
Screenshots from everyone on the stream are also welcome!
そして、皆さま、YouTubeやTikTokでご覧の皆さま、残念ながら...
And, everyone watching on YouTube or TikTok, unfortunately...
えー、無料チラ見せはここまでー！
Um, the free preview ends here!
ありがとうございます、現地のエールもいただきまして、え、まだまだ、一緒に盛り上がりたいみんなは、概要欄のリンクから配信サイトへ飛びますので、
Thank you, receiving cheers from the venue as well, for everyone who wants to get even more hyped together, please jump to the streaming site from the link in the description,
ここからが本番なので、たくさんの方に見ていただきたいと思っています！
since from here is the main event, I hope many people will watch!
え、今回のライブなんですが、これまであずきが歩んできた奇跡、そしてこれから歩んでいく未来、そのすべてをみんなと一緒に1つの物語として
Um, for today's live, all the miracles AZKi has walked through so far, and the future she will walk towards,
繋いでいくような一日にしたいと思っています。
I want to connect them all into a single story with everyone.
え、このライブで私の今の全ての音楽と共にまっすぐみんなに届けていきます！よろしくお願いします！
In this live, I will deliver all of myself right now straight to everyone along with the music! Thank you!
それじゃあ、どんどんいきますよ！最後まで一緒に楽しんでいこね！
Well then, let's keep going! Let's enjoy together until the end!
一緒に歌おう！みんなの声、聞かせて！
Let's sing together! Let me hear everyone's voices!
生きてくことをやめないでと 私が今歌う
Don't stop living, I sing now.
無料パートは終了いたしました！ご視聴ありがとうございました！
The sneak peek part of the show has ended. Thank you for watching.